David Castillo

Jersey City, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/David-Castillo/73e6baee4d24bcfb

4 years of experience programming in a variety of front and back end libraries/frameworks. As well as UX/ UI development and SEO Optimization skills. Expertise in developing and deploying Web / Mobile applications and / or websites in Windows, Linux, and Mac OS X environments. My experience has ranged across technologies such as:

Frontend: HTML5, CSS3 & pre-compilers (SASS/ Less), Bootstrap, Javascript/jQuery, Blaze, Angular, React

Backend: MeteorJs, NodeJs, PHP, MongoDB, MySQL, Wordpress, Drupal, Nginx

Cloud Providers / DevOps: AWS, Linux, Shell Scripting

Version Control Systems: Git Testing: Phantom.js, Jasmine Adobe: Photoshop & Illustrator Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Dabl3 - Macungie, PA - November 2014 to Present

- * My duties include taking photoshop mockups from our UX/UI Designer and turning them into fully functional front end interfaces using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript. And libraries such as jQuery, Bootstrap and SASS.
- * I created and assisted in server Integration, database design & architecture. As well as automating and setting up builds for iOS and Android from our application.
- * Built communication layers between the client, database and server.

Dabl3 Consumer App | http://www.dabl3.com/start/index.html Dabl3 Merchant App | http://www.dabl3.com/start/merchant.html

Senior Web Developer

Good Marketing Group - Trappe, PA - June 2015 to September 2016

My daily activities include developing and maintaining a user-friendly web content management system for use across internal web sites and client website development.

- I created site layout & user interface by using standard HTML5, CSS3, Javascript practices and full stack development platforms that run Mongo and Node.js in the backend.
- As the senior developer, I was in charge of 'making it happen', So I was constantly challenged by clients, internally at Good Marketing Group, and the industry as a whole to keep up with current web development technology and tools, while making sure it all works together across multiple applications.
- My duties were not only to make a website an on-line brochure but to make it a powerful sales & mar- keting tool.
- I grew as a developer, gained experience in on-demand deadlines, problem solving and being a team- player.

ACM http://www.acmix.com/

EWQA http://www.ewqa.org/

Salters Fireplace http://www.saltersfireplace.com/

Newtown Fireplace Shop http://www.newtownfireplaceshop.com/

Web Developer

Allentown, PA - September 2013 to December 2014

- Developed websites for various businesses utilizing technologies that include: HTML5, CSS3, Java- script/jQuery, PHP/MYSQL, Bootstrap & Wordpress.
- Elevated web presence using SEO concepts which had a positive impact to company's bottom line.
- Frequently complimented by clients about the quality of the websites and timely manner of completion.

EDUCATION

Asso in Liberal Arts

Hudson County Community College - Jersey City, NJ 2007 to 2009

University Academy Charter HS - Jersey City, NJ 2003 to 2007

LINKS

https://about.me/david-castillo

https://github.com/ecuanaso

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-castillo-aa0a2463?trk=nav_responsive_tab_profile